你在对我的书桌干什么
What are you doing to my desk?
盖茨去休假了
Oh, uh, well, Gates is on vacation,
所以我就想  何不跟老公一起在家做文书工作
so I figured why not do my paperwork from home with my husband?
如果...你愿意跟我一起玩旷工
That is, if you want to play hooky with me.
如果还是在工作  算是旷工吗
Is it technically playing hooky if we're working?
我们可以工作一会儿  然后再小睡一会儿
Well, we could work for a bit and then maybe take a nap.
我喜欢小睡
Oh, I like naps.
是啊  小睡最棒了
Yeah, naps are good.
稍等
Hang on.
是从私家侦探办公室转来的电话
Oh, it's a call forwarded from the P.I. office.
理查德·卡塞尔侦探社
Richard Castle investigations.
我就是
Speaking.
是的
Yes.
好的  我们20分钟后见
Oh, great. I will see you in 20 minutes.
好的  再见
All right. Bye.
我们俩终于有一次
Well, for once in the relationship,
是我接到电话了
I'm the one getting the call.
-我可能有客户  -卡塞尔  这太棒了
- I have a potential client. - Castle, that's fantastic.
不  不是的  我本打算陪你一天呢
No, it's not. No, I was gonna spend the day with you.
没事的  我也常说走就走
It's fine. It's not like I don't leave at a moment's notice
跑去查凶案啊
when there's a homicide.
如果我能尽快解决
Well, then maybe if I'm done soon,
我可以稍后回来  小睡一下
I can swing by later for, you know, a nap.
那你也只能自己小睡了
If you do, you'll be napping alone.
你要是要去办公室  那我也要去
Because if you're going to your office, then I'm going to mine.
马到成功啊  亲爱的
Knock 'em dead, babe.
你好啊
Well, hello, there.
一定是威特福德太太  我是理查德·卡塞尔
You must be Mrs. Whitfield. I'm Richard Castle.
哎呦  这是怎么了
Ooh, ouch. What happened there?
割伤了自己
Just cut myself.
理查德  不是吧
Richard. Really?
拜托  理查德·罗杰斯你真不记得我了吗
Come on, Richard Rodgers, you really don't remember me?
菲克罗夫特预科  化学课  我以前总抄你的
Faircroft prep, A.P. chem... I used to cheat off you.
-伊娃  伊娃·亨德里克斯  -伊娃  没错
- Eva! Eva Hendricks! - Eva, yeah.
现在是伊娃·威特福德了
Well, I'm... I'm Eva Whitfield now.
我现在是理查德·卡塞尔了
Oh, yeah. I'm Richard Castle now.
是啊  我读过你的书
I know. I've read your books,
关注了你和纽约警局的种种
followed your adventures with the NYPD.
听说你成了私家侦探
I heard you were a P.I.
我...
So, well, I, uh...
我们进去说吧
Uh, why don't we go inside and talk?
伊娃  告诉我  有什么要我做的
So, Eva, tell me, what can I do for you?
是我丈夫  科尔
Um, it's my husband, Cole.
他怎么了
What about him?
他是个股票经纪人
He's a stockbroker.
他很聪明  很帅气  很有魅力
He's, um... he's bright. He's handsome, charming.
我们结了婚  一切都那么美好
We got married, and it was so wonderful.
但这几年
Um, but then, in the last few years,
我们关系很僵
it's gotten so difficult.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
里克  我觉得他有外遇
Rick, I think he's cheating on me.
你为什么这么认为
And what makes you think that?
他的行为
The way he acts, um...
他的作息时间
The hours he keeps.
我大概早该有所准备
I mean, I should have known it was coming.
他坚持要我签婚前协议
He insisted on a prenup.
我就是...
I just...
我得知道真相
I have to find out the truth.
你能帮我吗
Can you help me?
我很抱歉  伊娃
I'm... I'm sorry, Eva.
但我一般不接这种工作
This is really not the kind of work I like to take on.
求你  里克  我就是想知道
Please, Rick, I-I just... I just want to know
我的婚姻是否还有丝毫值得我保护
if there's anything left in my marriage to fight for.
求你了
Please. Please.
好吧
Yeah, sure.
-真的  -我需要科尔的资料和一张近照
- Yeah? - Um, I'll just need Cole's information and a recent photo.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-简直荒谬  -就是
- That's ridiculous. - Completely...
不不  我今早把你弄醒了
No. No, no. I woke you up this morning.
你在听吗  是啊
Are you even listening? I mean... Yeah.
不不不
No, no, no, no.
我所说的是要知道
What I'm talking about here is knowing about...
你自己的实力  和得到该得到的
knowing what you have and getting what's right.
好吧
Oh, oh, okay, okay.
但你要知道  这获利可不小啊
But you do realize this could be a serious payday.
拜托  就是些小钱  斯科特
Please, it's chump change, Scott.
-科尔  -别耍滑头  科尔
- Cole... - Now, d-d-don't be glib, Cole.
他说的有道理
It's a legitimate point.
-斯科特  -怎么
- Scott. - What?
你信任我吗
Do you trust me?
我当然信任你
Of course, I trust you.
罗伯特
Robert?
是的
Yes.
那我们就不卖公司
Then we're not selling the company,
至少不能现在  不能以这个价
At least not at this time and not at that price.
-同意了吗  -同意  -同意
- Agreed? - Agreed. - Agreed.
-谢谢你来  -谢谢你
- Thanks for coming in. - Thank you.
好了
All right.
科尔  要搭车回办公室吗
Cole, you, uh, need a ride back to the office?
不用  我约了医生
No, I have a doctor's appointment.
好  我们回见
Okay, I will see you there.
罗伯特
Robert.
我有点难受  我可以去看医生
So I've got this pain, and, uh, I could either go see a doctor,
也可以去见你
or I could come see you.
嗯  听上去不错
Yeah. Oh, I like the sound of that.
我就来
Oh, I'm coming.
待会儿见
I'll see you soon.
那么她丈夫是在偷情
So her husband was having an affair,
你发现他偷腥了吗
and you caught him cheating?
抓了个正着  光着屁股呢
Caught him red-handed and bare-bottomed.
可怜的伊娃
Oh, poor Eva.
-她反应如何  -不太好  我刚刚半小时
- Well how is she taking it? - Not well, I spent the last half-hour
都在跟她通电话  她哭了
on the phone with her... lots of crying.
她在收拾东西准备离开他
She's packing up now to leave him.
-她要我先去给她送照片  -今晚吗
- She just wants me to drop these pictures by first. - Wait, tonight?
她想亲眼看到她婚姻结束的证据
Yeah, she wants to see firsthand that her marriage is over.
我还能怎么办  拒绝吗
What am I gonna tell her? No?
别让她靠在你肩上哭太久就行
Just don't let her cry on your shoulder too long.
贝克特  提醒我以后再也别接这种案子
Beckett, remind me never to take this kind of case again.
听着  是你说的
Look, you're the one who said
你会承担做私家侦探的后果
that you're gonna have to pay your dues as a P.I.
对  但那时我还不知道这意味着什么
Yeah, that before I knew what it meant.
要是我晚上给你做饭会不会让你好受点
Would it help at all if I cooked you dinner tonight?
可不止是好受一点
Immeasurably.
好  你什么时候能到家
Okay, what time can you make it home?
到韦斯切斯特然后再回来
Uh, Westchester and back?
再加上借肩膀的时间
Factoring in time for shoulder-crying,
8点39
8:39?
待会儿见  我爱你
I'll see you then. I love you.
-你都不试一下吗  -你能
- It's like you're not even trying. - Would you just pl-- hey.
卡塞尔的案子怎么样了
What's going on with Castle's case?
别转移话题
Now, don't try to change the subject.
我不说这个了  兄弟
I'm not talking about this anymore, bro.
你不说什么了
What are you not talking about?
莱恩缠着我不放就因为我目前不出去约会
Ryan is all up on my back 'cause I'm not dating anyone right now.
跟她讲讲原因
Tell her why.
-好吧  -听着  不久前
- Okay, so - - Look, a while ago,
我们买了情侣周末滑雪套餐  就下个月
we buy this couples weekend ski trip, and it's next month.
可惜蕾妮和埃斯波又分手了
Oh, except Lanie and Espo are broken up yet again.
怎么  你们是分手了  得了吧
What, you guys have. Come on.
他和珍妮也不能因此
Yeah, but that's no reason for him and Jenny
就认为我找不到其他人一块去
to think I can't find anyone else to take.
拜托  我不愁找不到女伴
I mean, come on. I have no problem getting girls.
但问题来了  你不用去找
But that's the thing. You don't have to get one.
珍妮和我已经找好了  我们有个朋友
Jenny and I already have. We -- we have a friend --
等等  你是在说要安排我相亲吗
Wait, are you talking about a blind date?
绝对不行
Oh, hell no!
埃斯波  听他说完
Espo, just hear him out.
她名叫史黛西  她很不错的
Her name is Stacy. She's fantastic.
有一家唱片行  还喜欢运动
She runs a music store. She's into sports.
我们跟她说了你的事  她想见见你
And we told her all about you. She wants to meet.
看看她的照片
Take a look at her picture.
得了吧  伙计
Come on, man.
她还行
She's all right.
还行而已  埃斯波  她美呆了
She's all right? Espo, she's stunning,
你连见她一面都不肯
and you won't even meet with her.
好吧  也许能见一面
Okay, maybe I will.
那也只是因为她这么期待见我
But only because she's so excited to meet me,
你懂的  我不太喜欢让女孩子失望
And you know I don't like to disappoint the ladies.
干得好
Nice. Good job.
我的天哪
Oh, my god.
站住
Hey! Hey, stop!
你在回家的路上了吗
Hey, are you on your way home?
贝克特  他杀了她
Beckett, he killed her.
他...杀了她  他
he -- he killed her. He --
贝克特  能听到我说话吗
Beckett, can you hear me?
该死
Damn it.
他开走了我的车
He took my car.
该死
Damn it.
卡塞尔  你在哪
Castle, where are you?
-贝克特她死了  -等等  慢点说
- Beckett, she's dead. She's dead. - Wait, slow down.
-怎么了  -伊娃被她丈夫杀死了
- What's -- what's going on? Eva was murdered by her husband.
他杀了她  我没能
He killed her, and I couldn't...
我没能阻止这件事
I couldn't stop it. I couldn't.
尼利警探  就像我之前跟你说过的
Detective Neely, as I already told you,
我跟踪科尔·威特福德来到这
I followed Cole Whitfield up here.
肯定是他打晕了我
He must have knocked me out
因为我醒来后  他走了  我的车也不见了
Because when I came to, he was gone and so was my car.
你起初为什么会去他家
And why did you go to his house in the first place?
我去给伊娃送照片
To give the photos to Eva.
也就是那时我听到了尖叫声
That's when I heard the screaming,
我还看到他从厨房把她拖了出来
and I saw him dragging her body through the kitchen.
我没来得及做什么  他就带着她开车走了
Before I could do anything, he drove off with her.
卡塞尔先生  据资料显示
Mr. Castle, it says here
你一个月前才拿到私人侦探的执照
you only got your P.I. license a month ago.
是的  所以呢
Yes, so?
所以你确定你看到了所发生的事吗
So, are you sure about what you saw?
当然  我很确定  我
Of course, I'm sure. I --
警探  我认识卡塞尔
Detective, I know Castle.
如果他说发生了那肯定就是的
If he says it happened, it did.
他说的部分内容被证实了
Part of his story checks out.
我们发现他的车停在一条
We found his car parked on an access road
离这儿大约一百米的通道上
about a hundred yards from here.
威特福德肯定是
Whitfield must have hid
为了逃跑躲在卡塞尔的车里
in Castle's car in order to make his getaway.
警探  我没有编故事
Detective, I am not making this up.
威特福德的房子就是犯罪现场
The Whitfield house is a crime scene.
如果我们去厨房就会找到血迹
If we go to that kitchen, we will find blood --
伊娃的血
Eva's blood.
我是警探尼利
I'm Detective Neely.
能跟你谈一会儿吗
Do you have a few minutes to talk?
可以  进来吧
Yeah, come on in.
发生了什么事
So, what is this all about?
我能为你们做些什么吗
What can I do for you folks?
威特福德先生  你的妻子伊娃在家吗
Mr. Whitfield, is your wife, Eva, home?
不在  怎么了
No. Why?
你知道她在哪吗
Do you know where she is?
我不知道  我20分钟前才到家
No, I don't. I got home about 20 minutes ago.
找到了这张伊娃留下的字条
Found this lovely note from Eva.
她发现了我有外遇  就离开了我
She figured out I'm having an affair, and she left me.
她离开了他
She left him?
我没法相信这个人  他伪造了那张字条
I can't believe this guy. He forged that note.
我都联系不上她
I can't even get in touch with her.
我给她打了一遍又一遍电话
I tried calling her. I tried calling her.
电话直接就跳转到语音信箱了
The phone just goes straight to voicemail.
你开的是一辆黑色的跑车吗
Do you drive a black model "S"?
不是  那是伊娃的车
No, that's... No, that's, uh, Eva's car.
-伊娃出什么事了吗  -我们还不确定
- Has something happened to Eva? - We're not quite sure,
你说你20分钟前才到家的吗
But you're saying you only got home 20 minutes ago?
是的  九点半左右
Yeah, right. Uh, around 9:30.
你今晚7点45的时候在哪
And where were you at 7:45 tonight?
我还在市里
I was, um... I was still in the city.
我在工作
I was at work.
你知道吗  我想我得再去添点酒
You know what? I-I think I need a refill.
不好意思
Excuse me.
他在撒谎  他在胡说八道
He's lying. He's lying about everything.
如果你说的对  那厨房肯定会有血迹
If you're right, there should be blood evidence in the kitchen.
就在这
It was here.
就在这里  他肯定把这里弄干净了
It happened right here. He must have cleaned it up.
否则他怎么会这么轻易就让我们进来
Why else would he invite us so freely into his house?
如果真是他干的  那他做得太好了
If he did, he did a hell of a good job of it.
紫外线照射看不出血迹残留
U.V. shows no sign of residue.
-卡塞尔  -凯特  我知道我看到了什么
- Castle... - Kate, I know what I saw.
那里  那里
T-there! There!
看见了吧  我就知道
See? I knew it.
知道什么  怎么回事
Knew what? What is going on?
先生  这里有血迹残留的痕迹
Sir, there's blood residue here.
威特福德先生  你知道血是哪来的吗
Mr. Whitfield, do you know where this came from?
知道
Yes.
我妻子总是笨手笨脚的
My wife is a klutz.
她把罐子打破了  收拾的时候割破了手
She broke a jar and cut her hand cleaning it up.
血流得到处都是  直到她用绷带包住
Bled everywhere until she finally bandaged it.
为什么  你们为什么要找血迹残留
Why -- why are you looking for blood residue?
你们是认为我对我妻子做了什么吗
Are you suggesting that I did something to my wife?
不  我们没有这么想  威特福德先生
No, we're not suggesting, Mr. Whitfield.
出去
Get out.
离开我家
Get out of my house.
赶紧离开
Get out now.
你起来多长时间了
How long have you been up?
可能是他回到家
He probably came home,
看到伊娃准备要离开他
saw that Eva was about to leave him,
所以一时冲动杀了她
and killed her in a fit of rage.
我跟她说过一切都会没事的
I told her everything was gonna be all right.
我向她保证过
I promised her.
对不起  宝贝
I'm sorry, babe.
尼利警探那有什么消息吗
Have you heard from Detective Neely?
她说搜寻小队在树林里
She said that search teams
什么也没发现
didn't find anything in the woods.
肯定的
Yeah.
因为科尔明白他不能把她留在那
That's because Cole knew he couldn't leave her out there,
因为他知道我看到了  所以他把她放到车上
not once I was onto him, so he put her back in the car
然后把车和尸体分别遗弃掉了
and dumped it and the body someplace else.
韦斯切斯特的警察已经对伊娃的车发出了全境通告
Westchester has got a BOLO out on Eva's car,
也对她的信用卡做了标记
and they've flagged her credit cards.
他们找到她手机的位置了吗
Have they pinged her cellphone?
他们试过  可是手机不是关机了就是没电了
They tried, but it's either off or dead.
我看是没电了[死了]
Yeah, I want to go with dead.
他的不在场证据呢
What about his alibi?
他当时不是像他说的在工作
Well, he wasn't at work like he said.
他的工作伙伴说
His business partners said
他不是晚上八点离开的  而是六点
that he left at 6:00 P.M., not at 8:00.
有足够的时间让他在7:45回到韦斯切斯特
Plenty of time to get back to Westchester by 7:45.
可是当尼利警探
But when Detective Neely
质问他时  他又改口了
confronted him about it, he revised his story.
他说他当时跟他的情人
He said that he was with his mistress,
泰勒·麦金利  也就是
Taylor Mckinley, that woman
你照到的那个女人  一直待到晚上八点
that you took pictures of, until 8:00 P.M.
我们要跟她谈谈
We need to talk to her.
卡塞尔  我没有管辖权
Castle, I don't have any jurisdiction.
这不是我的案子
This isn't my case.
是的  但这是我的案子  伊娃雇了我
Yes, but it's my case. Eva hired me.
她是我的朋友
She was my friend,
而且她是在我眼前被杀的
and he killed her right in front of me.
好吧  我去跟他情人谈
Okay. I'll talk to the mistress.
但只有我一个人  你对这事有私人感情
But just me, not you. You're too close to this.
怎么了  我跟他有婚外情  他老婆走了
So? We had an affair, and his wife left.
有什么大不了  这种事每天都有
What's the big deal? That stuff happens every day.
可是不是每天都有老婆失踪
Except wives don't go missing every day.
现在就说她失踪有点为时过早吧
It's a little soon to say she's missing, isn't it?
我确定她会回来的
I'm sure she'll be back.
麦金利小姐  你认识威特福德先生多久了
Ms. Mckinley, how long have you known Mr. Whitfield?
从他去年上我的瑜伽课开始认识的
Since he started my yoga class a year ago.
婚外情是什么时候开始的
And when did the affair begin?
一周之后
About a week later.
怎么了
What?
他很帅  而且很有钱
He's hot, and rich.
他昨晚几点去你家的
What time did he come to your apartment last night?
我跟另一个警探说过
Like I told the other detective,
他六点左右来的  刚过八点以后走的
he showed up right around 6:00 and he left just after 8:00.
期间这段时间你们俩都在屋里
So, the two of you were in the apartment the whole time?
是的
Yep.
你怎么看
Well, what did you think?
她很有对抗性
She was confrontational
而且对问题准备得也太充分了
and a little too ready with her answers.
你觉得她在撒谎
You think she's lying?
去她住的地方
Go down to her building,
问问有没有人昨晚看到科尔·威特福德在那
see if anyone else saw Cole Whitfield there last night.
还要再查一下威特福德先生
And let's look into Mr. Whitfield,
看看他还有没有别的事瞒着我们
find out what else he's hiding from us.
好的
All right.
袋子里有什么  科尔  你要带它们去哪
What's in the bags, Cole, and where are you taking them?
-你在干什么  -我...
- What the hell are you doing? - I-I was...
你先是指控我杀人
You accuse me of murder,
然后又来我家跟踪我
then you come stalking around my home?
你有什么病
What the hell is your damage, man?
-什么  我有病  -是的
- What? My damage? - Yeah.
我又没杀了自己的妻子
I'm not the one who killed my wife.
你简直是神经病  伊娃还活着
You're insane, you know that? Eva's alive.
她二十分钟前刚给我打过电话
She just called me 20 minutes ago.
你骗人
You're a liar.
我也想
Yeah, I wish.
因为她让我去死
Because she told me to go screw myself
还把我们的联合银行账户都清空了
and that she cleaned out our joint bank accounts.
你不相信我  可以查查我的银行账户
Yeah, you don't believe me, you can check with my bank.
你们搜查我房子时
While you guys were searching my house,
那个贱人从我这偷走了七百四十万
the bitch stole $7.4 million from me.
威特福德先生  有什么事吗
Mr. Whitfield, is there a problem?
是的  这个人在骚扰我
Yes. This man is harassing me.
你什么都证明不了
Hey, you'll never prove a thing.
他...
He...
你疯了吗  你是怎么想的
Are you crazy? What were you thinking?
你昨晚也见到他了  他很自大
You saw him last night. He's cocky.
自大的男人会怎样
And what do all cocky men do?
犯错
Make mistakes.
没错
Exactly.
等等  你是说我  对吧
Wait, you're talking about me now, aren't you?
你是唯一的目击者  你这是在毁掉
You're the only witness, and you are ruining
你的可信度  而我却一直在帮你
your credibility when I'm trying to help you.
要是盖茨知道了怎么办
What if this gets back to Gates?
我只是想找些证据
I'm just trying to find some proof.
现在  证据对科尔有利
Right now, the proof lies with Cole.
伊娃的通话记录显示她今早9:35给他打过电话
Eva's phone records confirm a call to him at 9:35 this morning,
昨晚还有740万美元
And there's also that $7.4 million transfer
转入了瑞士银行账户
to a Swiss bank account last night.
没错  他是在创造合理的疑点
Yes, he's creating reasonable doubt,
营造出她偷了他的钱财
Building a narrative that she stole from him,
然后跑路的假象
That she's on the run.
所以我们才找不到尸体  他的计划就是这样的
That's why we can't find the body. That's his plan.
我刚从那位情妇的公寓回来
I just got back from the mistress' apartment building.
没人记得昨晚看到过威特福德
No one remembers seeing Whitfield at all last night.
证明他并不在那里
Proving he wasn't there.
那只能证明没人看到过他
Proving that no one saw him.
没有尸体的话
Without a body,
我们需要些比这更确凿的证据
We're gonna need something more solid than that.
嘿  你们猜怎么着
Hey, guess what.
调查发现威特福德之前就结过婚
Turns out Whitfield was married before,
在洛杉矶结的
In Los Angeles.
玛罗琳·威特福德
Mallory Whitfield --
她曾经拥有一笔价值几百万的遗产
She had an inheritance worth several million dollars.
-曾经  -是的  她在徒步旅行途中去世了
- Had? - Yeah, she died in a hiking accident
就在洛杉矶国家森林公园中  跌入了一个峡谷中
In Angeles national forest -- fell into a ravine.
-猜猜唯一的目击证人是谁  -她丈夫科尔
- Guess who the only witness was. - Her husband, Cole.
没错  警方曾试图以谋杀罪调查他
Bingo. The cops tried to make a murder case against him,
但他应对得滴水不漏
but he had all the answers.
他们无法对他提起有力的控诉
They could never make any of the charges stick.
她的全部财产都转移到了科尔手中
Her entire estate went to Cole,
他正是借助那笔钱来创业发财的
which he used to start his business and build his fortune.
他之前就逃脱了惩罚
So, he got away with it before,
现在他又打算故技重施
And now he's trying to do it again.
这根本不是冲动犯罪  是他早就计划好的
This was no crime of passion. He planned the whole thing.
科尔的第一任妻子死因很可疑
So, Cole's first wife dies suspiciously,
然后第二任妻子也消失了
And then the second one disappears.
那不可能是巧合
No way that's a coincidence.
那家伙就是个黑寡妇  或者说黑鳏夫
This guy's a black widow -- or, rather, black widower.
只不过这次没有尸体
Only this time, there's no body.
他是想制造伊娃还活着的假象
He's trying to create the illusion that Eva's still alive.
是的  他为了让这假象显得真实
Yeah, and he's going to some major trouble
还真是煞费苦心
to make that illusion seem real.
卡塞尔  你之前说科尔·威特福德
Castle, you said that Cole Whitfield
今早是在韦斯切斯特的家里  对吧
was at home in Westchester this morning, right?
没错  他一直没离开过
That's right. He never left.
根据我刚刚从伊娃的手机里获得的数据
Well, I just got the data back from Eva's phone.
打给科尔的电话是从曼哈顿的一座信号塔传送的
the call to Cole pinged off a tower in Manhattan.
他肯定是叫别人用伊娃的手机打那通电话的
He must have had someone use Eva's phone to make that call.
他有同谋
He's got an accomplice.
不管那人是谁
And whoever that is
是在靠近第31大道和第4大道的地方打电话的
made that call somewhere near 31st and 4th.
那正好是我拍摄这些照片的地方
That's where I took those photos.
他的情妇泰勒就住在那附近
His mistress, Taylor, lives on that block.
如果泰勒为他的不在场证明撒了谎
If Taylor lied about his alibi,
或许那通电话就是她打的
she might have made that phone call.
你们去把她请来警局一趟吧
Why don't you guys go and pick her up?
该死  那我只能取消
Oh, damn, that means I'm gonna have to cancel
-跟史黛西的午餐之约了  -你不能取消
- that lunch date with Stacy, bro. - No, no, no, no, no, you can't.
你必须留下良好的第一印象
Uh, you have to make a good first impression.
老天啊  算了
Oh, for heaven's sake. You know what?
你去约会吧  莱恩和我去带她过来
Go enjoy your date. Ryan and I will go and get her.
我已经回答过你们所有的问题了
I already answered all your questions.
现在我们有更多的问题了
And now we have more
因为现在出现了新的信息
Because new information has come to light.
什么新信息
What new information?
在谈到那个之前  我想再重复一下
Before we get to that, I'd like to revisit
我们上次见面时  你所说的话
something that you said at our last meeting.
你说从昨晚6点到8点
You said that Cole was at your apartment
科尔都在你的公寓里
between 6:00 and 8:00 last night.
你现在仍坚持这种说法不变吗
Are you still saying that now?
是的
Yep.
但你的邻居都说没看见他
None of your neighbors saw him.
他这人做事很谨慎小心
Well, he's very discreet.
是他叫你说他当时在你的公寓里的吗
Did he tell you to say that he was at your apartment?
不是
No.
他有没有叫你用别人的手机给他打电话
Did he ask you to call him from someone else's cellphone?
泰勒  什么都别说了
Taylor, don't say another word.
我是奥德丽·哈斯金斯  麦金利小姐的律师
Aubrey Haskins, attorney for ms. Mckinley.
-等等  你是谁  -放心  是科尔派我来的
- Wait, who are you? - It's okay. Cole sent me.
我是他公司的总律师顾问
I'm general counsel for his company.
-让我来跟警方谈  -泰勒  听我说
- Just let me do the talking. - Taylor, listen to me.
如果你提供了假的不在场证明  你也会变成同谋
If you provided a false alibi, that makes you an accomplice.
那可是要坐牢的
That means jail.
到底是什么事的同谋啊
Accomplice to what, exactly?
-杀害伊娃·威特福德  -伊娃并没有死
- The murder of Eva Whitfield. - Eva's not dead.
科尔今早还跟她说过话呢
Cole spoke with her this morning.
或者他是跟一个用她手机的人说的话
Or he spoke to someone using her cellphone.
那通电话定位的信号塔
That call pinged off of a tower
就在你公寓附近  时间是上午9:35
right next to your apartment building at 9:35 A.M.
-探长  除非你有证据  -等等
- Detective, unless you have proof -- wait.
你是在说我就是打那个电话的人吗
Are you accusing me of making that call?
我9:35时在瑜伽馆工作呢
I was at work at 9:35 at the yoga studio.
泰勒  我有你的工作安排表
Taylor, I've got your schedule.
你上午是不工作的
You don't work in the mornings.
本来是这样  但他们打电话叫我过去
No, but I got called in to cover
为另一个生病的教练代班
for another instructor who was sick.
我从上午9:30到11:00一直在那里
I was there from 9:30 a.M. to 11:00.
你可以去查的
You can check that.
我看到此为止吧  探长
We're done here, detective.
真是狡诈的一招
That was a crafty move.
科尔派他的内务律师来让他的女朋友闭嘴
Cole sent his in-house lawyer to silence his girlfriend.
他要把这事控制在家庭范围内
He's keeping this thing contained, in the family.
是啊  但现在泰勒有了律师
Yeah, but now that Taylor's lawyered up,
我们要怎么攻破她啊
How are we gonna break her?
就是深挖她供述的信息
By digging into her story.
我打去她工作的地方  核实下她的不在场证明
I'll call her work and check into her alibi.
小伙伴  约会进行得怎么样啊
Partner. How did the date go?
我们能到这边来谈吗
Can we talk about it out here?
你觉得史黛西怎么样
What did you think of Stacy?
天啊  她真的很赞
Oh, man, she was great.
直到后来我发现她有跟踪狂的嫌疑
Until I started getting a stalker vibe from her.
-什么  -没错  当时我们正在吃开胃菜
- What? - Yeah, we were right in the middle of appetizers,
然后她告诉我  我在三项全能运动比赛中
And that's when she told me that the blue shorts
穿的那件蓝色短裤
I was wearing during the triathlon
让我的腿显得很性感  那倒是实话
made my legs look sexy, which is true,
但她怎么知道我参赛了
But how did she even know I competed,
更别提我当时穿的是什么颜色的短裤了
never mind what color shorts I was wearing?
就在那时她告诉我
And that's when she told me
她是在我的个人资料里看到那张照片的
that she saw the photo on my profile.
你觉得这很好笑吗
Oh, this is funny to you?
你居然偷偷替我注册了配对网账号
You signed me up for Match.com behind my back?
算起来应该是珍妮干的
Well, technically, Jenny did.
我只是帮你修改了下资料
I've, I've only been managing your profile.
你觉得我不会发现吗
Did you think I wouldn't find out?
我差点抓了那女孩
I almost arrested that girl.
我们以为你会不可自拔地迷上她
Well, we were hoping that you'd be so into her
然后把这事忘了
that you'd just let it go.
你哪根筋不对  我自己能找到约会对象
What the hell is wrong with you? I can find my own dates.
我知道你能  可你还没找到呢
I know, but you haven't.
而周末的滑雪之行就要到了  所以
And the ski weekend is coming up, so...
听我说
Look, look, look, look.
我们只是想帮你而已
We were just trying to help.
我不需要你们帮我
I don't need your help.
这事没完
This isn't over.
瑜伽中心的经理证实
The manager at the yoga studio
泰勒那天确实是从早上九点半
verified that Taylor was at work from 9:30
-工作到十一点  -经理在说谎
- till 11:00 A.M. - Then the manager's lying.
卡塞尔  她带的班可有30个人
Castle, she had a classroom full of 30 people.
电话不是她打的
She didn't make that call,
打电话的人肯定算准了
but whoever did made sure to do it
自己就在泰勒那栋楼旁边
right by Taylor's building.
有人想把我们的注意力转移到泰勒身上
Which means someone wants us to believe it was Taylor.
如果她不是临时被叫去上班
And we would have
我们的确会这么认为
if she didn't get called into work.
被叫去上班
Called into work.
当然了
Of course.
泰勒被叫去上班
Taylor getting called into work
这件事是幕后黑手
is the one thing the person behind this
无法预料到的
couldn't have foreseen.
-那个人就是科尔 -不是
- That person being Cole. - No.
-不是吗  -不是
- No? - No.
贝克特  这场谋杀是被设计好的
Beckett, the murder was staged.
整件事就像小说一样
This whole thing, it's a work of fiction.
这就是部希区柯克经典电影
I-it's a Hitchcock movie with me
而我扮演目击者
cast as the witness.
我就是《迷魂记》里的吉米·斯图尔特
I'm Jimmy Stewart in "Vertigo."
我们之所以没找到尸体
The reason we haven't found a body
是因为根本就没有尸体
is because there is no body.
伊娃还活着
Eva's still alive.
Eva's alive?
卡塞尔  之前你明明不是这么想的
Castle, that's not what you believed a moment ago.
我刚刚才反应过来
It didn't hit me until just now.
伊娃想让科尔看起来像凶手
Eva is the one person who would want Cole
而他的情人看起来像共犯
to look like a murderer and his mistress an accomplice.
你目睹科尔杀了伊娃
Wait, you saw Cole kill Eva.
你确实看到了  不是吗
I mean, y-you did, didn't you?
我看见的是她想让我看见的
I saw what she wanted me to see.
这就是为何那晚她想让我把照片送过去
That's why she wanted me to drop off the photos that night.
伊娃策划好了这一切
Eva's been behind this from the start,
而我是电影里那个易骗的私家侦探
and I'm the gullible P.I. that fell for it.
她为什么要如此大费周章
Why would she go to that length?
因为伊娃要的不只是婚姻
Because Eva wanted more than just out of the marriage.
她想让科尔受尽折磨
She wanted Cole to suffer.
她设局陷害他
She set him up.
他说她打电话给他
He swore that she called him
因为她确实打了电话
because she did call him.
她还向瑞士银行账号里
She also transferred
转了740万美金
the $7.4 million to the Swiss bank account.
那是她逃之夭夭的钱
It's her walking-away money.
贝克特  我是对的
I'm telling you, Beckett, I am right about this.
什么时候
When?
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
卡塞尔  很抱歉  但是
Castle, I'm sorry but--
不  贝克特  我知道听上去很奇怪
No, Beckett, I know it sounds crazy,
但伊娃还活着
but Eva is still alive.
她死了
No, she's not.
他们在哈德逊河发现了她的尸体
They found her body in the Hudson.
伊娃死了
Eva's dead.
伊娃不可能真死
There is no way Eva is really dead.
希区柯克的经典电影里  这不会是她的尸体
In a classic Hitchcockian twist, it won't be her body.
记好了
Mark my words.
那我们从河里捞上来的是什么
Then who did we pull out of the river?
伊娃的替身
Someone who can pass for Eva.
那我们就测一下她的指纹
Okay, we'll run her prints.
这能够说明她到底是谁了
That should clear up whether it's Eva or not.
只不过她的指纹已经被换掉
Except her prints will be altered,
脸部无法辨认
her face, unrecognizable,
伊娃的完美犯罪计划
all part of Eva's plan to commit the perfect crime.
你会明白的
You'll see.
她看起来真像伊娃
Whoa. She looks just like Eva.
那是因为她就是伊娃
That's because it is Eva.
指纹吻合  她就是你们要找的人
Her prints match. This is your girl.
这不可能
No, it can't be.
我还查了她的牙科记录  卡塞尔  就是她
I checked her dental records, too, Castle. It's her.
我也希望我能说不是她
I wish I could tell you it wasn't.
我觉得死因是
I take it that the cause of death
遭到钝物重击
is blunt-force trauma.
看起来顶骨区域
It looks like a massive skull fracture
出现大面积骨折  不过尸体才送来
in the parietal region, but she just came in,
我只做了初步检测
so I've only done a preliminary exam.
一旦验尸完成  我会打电话给你
Once I've finished my autopsy, I'll give you a call.
好的
Okay.
卡塞尔  对于你朋友的事我很抱歉
Castle, I'm sorry about your friend.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
现在我们有了尸体  也许有了些优势
Now that we have a body, maybe that will give us some leverage.
泰勒  我们得谈谈
Taylor, we need to talk.
我的律师让我不要跟你说话
My lawyer said not to speak with you.
那好  听我说就行
Fine. Then just listen.
我不知道科尔跟你说了什么
I don't know what Cole told you,
不过他妻子死了
but his wife is dead.
不到两小时前  她的尸体被人发现了
Her body was found less than two hours ago.
天呐
Oh, my God.
泰勒
Listen, Taylor,
如果你想免受牢狱之灾
if you want to stay out of prison,
是时候坦白了
now's the time to tell us the truth.
哈斯金斯小姐  欢迎回来
Ms. Haskins, welcome back.
看起来本案中你代表所有人啊
You seem to be representing everyone in this matter.
在开始之前
Before we begin,
威特福德先生来此的唯一目的
Mr. Whitfield is here only because you said
是因为你们声称有他妻子的下落
you have information on his wife's whereabouts.
科尔  你说你今早和伊娃说了话
Cole, you said that you spoke with Eva this morning.
她说什么了
What did she say?
她说一切都结束了  她要离开这里
She said it was over and that she was leaving town.
警探  你到底找到威特福德夫人没有
Detective, did you find Mrs. Whitfield or not?
我们在哈德逊河找到了她的尸体
Oh, we found her... in the Hudson...
她是你杀的
murdered by you.
那是个谎言
That's a lie.
泰勒已经把你供出来了
Taylor gave you up.
她说昨晚你并没有跟她在一起
She said that you weren't with her last night.
没有我在场你就跟我的当事人谈话了吗
You spoke to my client without me?
她放弃了她的权利
She waived her right.
威特福德先生  如果昨晚你没有跟泰勒在一起
Mr. Whitfield, if you weren't with Taylor last night,
-那你在哪里  -不要回答
- then where were you? - Don't answer that.
你要提出起诉吗
Are you pressing charges?
无法避免了  是的
Inevitably, yeah.
科尔  我们走
Cole, let's go.
我知道是你干的
I know you did it.
-不许你跟我的当事人说话  -是你杀了她
- Do not speak to my client. - You killed her.
我看见你了
I saw you.
卡塞尔  卡塞尔
Castle, Castle, hey.
警官  你们这算是什么警局
Detective, what the hell kind of precinct is this?
带上你的当事人赶紧离开
Just take your client and go home.
-用不了多久我们还会去找你的  -我们走
- We'll be coming back for you soon enough. - Let's go.
卡塞尔  你在干什么
Castle, what was that?
我知道这样不对  对不起
I know. I know. I'm sorry.
卡塞尔  你压力太大了  回家休息一下
Castle, you're stressed. Go home and try to relax.
我会没事的
I'll be fine.
我知道  不过现在你必须赶紧离开
I know you will. But right now, you just need to walk away.
是啊
Yeah.
是啊  你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
好的
Okay.
蕾妮  有什么发现
Lanie, what do you got?
在尸检过程中  我发现
During the autopsy, I discovered
伊娃左手食指的指甲
that Eva's fingernail on her left index
从中间断开了
had been split down the middle.
有三根头发被夹在裂缝当中
Wedged in that crack were these three hairs.
这些头发一定是在挣扎中留下的
These hairs must have gotten transferred during the struggle.
差不多
Most likely.
蕾妮  最快多久可以检测出结果
Lanie, how fast can you test these?
科尔被怀疑杀害
Cole's DNA is still on file
其第一任妻子的档案中还留有他的DNA
from when he was suspected of murdering his first wife.
我已经检测过了  结果相吻合
I already ran them, and they're a match.
科尔·威特福德就是凶手
Cole Whitfield is your man.
威特福德先生
Mr. Whitfield!
威特福德先生  我们奉令逮捕你
Mr. Whitfield, we have a warrant for your arrest.
没有回应  前门和后门都没有
No answer, not a the front or the back.
他的越野车还在车道上
His S.U.V.'s in the driveway.
-需要破门吗  -没那个必要
- Should we take the door? - There's no need.
威特福德先生
Mr. Whitfield?
别躲了
Show yourself.
不要再做无畏的抵抗了
Let's not make this harder than it has to be.
你没事吧
Are you doing okay?
我只是没想到这个故事会以这样的形式终结
I just never thought the story would end like this.
是的  我猜科尔也没想到
Yeah, I bet Cole didn't either.
是的  可是自杀
Yeah, but suicide?
法医怎么说
What did the M.E. say?
看起来是他自己把绳子套在脖子上的
That it looks like he wrapped the cord around his neck
然后从阳台跳下来了
and stepped off the balcony.
我很抱歉
Look, I'm sorry.
我知道这不是你想要的结局
I know that this isn't how you wanted it to end.
贝克特
Beckett?
贝克特  你还没睡吗
Beckett, are you still awake?
睡了
No.
太好了  有些事让我心烦
Good. Something's bothering me.
是吗  有些人也让我很心烦
Yeah? Something's bothering me, too.
像科尔那样的人怎么会自杀呢
Why would a guy like Cole commit suicide?
因为像科尔那样的人
Because a guy like Cole
面对不了入狱的局面
didn't think he could face going to prison.
像他那样富有且关系网庞大的人
As wealthy and connected as he was?
真的可能会进监狱吗
W-would he have even gone to prison?
案件中针对他的证据都是间接的
The case against him was circumstantial.
他完全有可能在法庭上打赢官司
He could have beaten it in court.
很显然  他不这样认为
Well, evidently, he didn't think so.
做得太干净了
It's too clean.
卡塞尔  别再胡思乱想了
Castle, stop chasing the mice in your head.
可是万一它们指引我走向真相呢
But what if they're leading me to the truth?
那等我们明早再研究吧
Then we'll deal with it in the morning.
卡塞尔
Castle?
来的路上给你带了咖啡
Hey, I brought you some coffee on my way to --
看来你肯定不需要什么咖啡了
You definitely don't need any more coffee.
这是什么
What is this?
时间线
Uh, timeline.
红线是伊娃  绿线是科尔  蓝线是泰勒
Eva is red, Cole is green, and Taylor is blue.
已经结案的案子的时间线吗
A timeline for a case that's closed?
还没结案  科尔并不是自杀
Not yet. Cole didn't kill himself.
有什么根据
Based on what?
根据他的性格
Based on his personality.
科尔很自大  自视甚高
Cole is cocky. He's entitled.
他那么自恋  绝不可能会自杀
He's far too much of a narcissist to commit suicide.
如果他不是自杀  那就说明他是被谋杀的
So if he didn't kill himself, that means he was murdered.
卡塞尔  这个假设真的很大
Castle, that's a pretty big "If."
会改变一切
It changes everything.
因为如果科尔不是自杀
Because if Cole didn't kill himself,
那就说明伊娃不是他杀的
it follows that he didn't murder Eva.
凶手另有其人
Someone else did.
所以他的死被伪装成自杀
That's why he was staged to look like a suicide,
这样警察就会得出他畏罪自杀的结论
so the police would conclude that he was the guilty party.
杀害科尔的人也杀了伊娃
Then whoever killed Cole also killed Eva.
谁会做这些事呢
And who would that be?
那个假装袭击她的人
The man I saw "Attacking" her.
也是在树林里打晕我的那个人
Whoever hit me in the woods.
可你说袭击她的人是科尔
Who you said was Cole.
他让我相信那个人是科尔
He wanted me to believe he was Cole.
那都是在演戏
It was just all theater.
好吧  卡塞尔  假设
Okay, Castle, let's say for a second,
有人溜进房子假扮成科尔
that someone snuck into the house disguised as Cole,
袭击了伊娃  可是他怎么会知道
and attacked Eva. How could they possibly know
那时刚好你会在那里目击这一切呢
that you were gonna be there to witness it?
他一定是跟伊娃串通好的
Well, he had to have been in on it with Eva.
如果伊娃策划了这一切  那她为什么会死呢
If Eva is a part of the setup, then why is she in the morgue?
因为这是希区柯克式的反转
Because, in classic Hitchcock fashion,
她的同谋者出卖了她
her co-conspirator double-crossed her.
"威特福德和加罗威公司的企业章程"
"The articles of incorporation for Whitfield & Galloway."
科尔的公司吗
Cole's company?
我用了两盒甜甜圈
It took me two boxes of cronuts
从办事员的办公室弄到这个
to get that out of the county clerk's office.
科尔和他的合伙人斯科特·加罗威
See, Cole and his partner Scott Galloway
一起合作  但是章程上却写着
were in business together, but in that document,
万一其中一个发生什么意外
it says if anything happens
另外一个得以掌管公司
to one of them, the other one gains control of the company.
你是说斯科特·加罗威
You're suggesting that Scott Galloway
是伊娃的同谋者
was Eva's co-conspirator.
我听了我在餐厅偷录的他们的谈话
I listened to the recording I made of their lunch.
这获利可不小啊
This could be a serious payday.
拜托  就是些小钱  斯科特
Please, it's chump change, Scott.
别耍滑头  科尔
Now, d-d-don't be glib, Cole.
有人出高价收购他们的公司
They were getting a major offer to buyout their firm,
科尔不赞同被收购
An offer that Cole was against,
于是我对斯科特·加罗威进行了信用核查
so I did a credit check on Scott Galloway.
他欠下巨额债款
He was in massive debt.
被收购可以解决他的窘境
A buyout would have fixed all that.
但想要收购顺利进行
But in order for that to happen,
他需要掌控公司
he needed control of the company.
伊娃想跟他离婚  她想让科尔受到惩罚
Eva wanted out of her marriage, and she wanted Cole punished.
于是他们联手除掉了科尔
So they teamed up to take Cole out of the picture.
卡塞尔  没有证据支持这个推理
Castle, there's no evidence that supports this.
是斯科特·加罗威  一定是
It was Scott Galloway. It has to be.
贝克特  求你查查斯科特的不在场证明
Beckett, will you please just check Scott's alibi?
你会为我这么做吗
Would you do that for me?
我会的  但听着  伊娃是你的朋友
I will. But listen to me. Eva was your friend.
她来到你的办公室找你帮忙
She came here to this very office and asked for your help,
现在她死了  你觉得自己有责任破案
and now she's dead, and you feel responsible,
那样会让你发疯的
and that can make you see ghosts.
我们现在开始调查斯科特·加罗威了  为什么
Wait, we're looking into Scott Galloway now? Why?
所有证据不都指向科尔·威特福德是凶手吗
I thought everything pointed to Cole Whitfield being the killer.
是的
It does.
就是说你相信卡塞尔的理论
Oh, you believe this theory of Castle's?
我认为他对过太多次
I believe that he's been right too many times
不得不考虑一下
not to consider it.
我正想打给你呢
Hey, I was just about to call you.
听着  我仔细想了想
Listen, I've been thinking about it,
算是后见之明吧  你是对的
and with the benefit of hindsight, y-you're right.
我看得出我可能会越陷越深
I can see how I might have tumbled down the rabbit hole.
斯科特·加罗威可能跟整件事没有关系
Scott Galloway probably has nothing to do with this.
是的
No, he doesn't.
证实了他的不在场证明  但你说对了  卡塞尔
His alibi checks out, but you were right, Castle.
我们找到了证据证明科尔没有杀害伊娃
We found proof that Cole didn't kill Eva.
我知道是谁干的
And I know who did.
斯科特·加罗威洗清了嫌疑
Scott Galloway is in the clear.
在7点45  伊娃被袭时
At 7:45, when Eva was supposedly attacked,
他在观看儿子的篮球比赛
he was at his son's basketball game.
但你说找到了科尔没杀伊娃的证据  是什么
But you said you had proof that Cole didn't kill Eva. What is it?
你关于斯科特的推理没有成立
Your theory about Scott didn't pan out,
但我们还是做了尽职调查
but we did due diligence
调查了科尔生活中的其他人
and looked at other people in Cole's life,
然后我们找到了这个
and that's when we found this.
那是科尔的SUV吗
Is that Cole's S.U.V.?
是的  街道监控显示科尔在这栋房子里
It is. Street cams show that Cole was in this house,
在斯卡斯代尔区  从下午6点到8点
which is in Scarsdale, from 6:00 and 8:00 p.m.
因此科尔·威特福德不可能是你所看到
Therefore, Cole Whitfield could not have been the man
袭击伊娃的那个人
that you saw attack eva.
还有一个有趣的发现
And here's another fun fact.
科尔定期拜访那里
Cole visited that house on a regular basis
总是在下午6点到8点这个时间段
between 6:00 and 8:00 p.m.
这是谁的房子
Whose house is that?
罗伯特·詹姆斯
Robert James,
威特福德和加罗威公司的另一个总经理
one of the other executives at Whitfield & Galloway.
午餐时他也在
He was at the lunch,
科尔去罗伯特·詹姆斯家干什么
but what was Cole doing at Robert James' house?
他不是去见罗伯特·詹姆斯的
Oh, he wasn't there to see Robert James.
我们发现他总是要在单位加班
Turns out, he always worked late at the office,
詹姆斯夫人在家
but Mrs. James was there.
开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
科尔跟同事的妻子出轨  这是第二段婚外情
Cole was having a second affair with his colleague's wife?
所以他才会谎称那晚所在地
Which is probably why he lied about where he was that night.
妻子承认了二人出轨
The wife confirmed the affair,
但她以为没人知道
but she thought that nobody knew about it.
凶案当晚  能确认詹姆斯在威特福德家附近吗
Can we put Robert James near the Whitfield house that night?
当然能确认
Damn right we can.
詹姆斯先生  感谢你赶过来
Mr. James, uh, thank you so much for coming in.
别客气  不过我不知道能帮上什么忙
Of course, though I'm not quite sure how I can help you.
你可以先告诉我前天晚上8点
Well, you can start by telling me where you were
你在哪里
two nights ago at 8:00 p.m.
我加班  在办公室
Well, I work late. I was at the office.
不  你不在
No, you weren't.
这是你晚上7点04在过路收费亭
In fact, this is you at a tollbooth at 7:04 p.m.
前往科尔位于韦斯切斯特的家
heading to Cole's house in Westchester.
不需要撒谎
There is no need for lying here.
当伊娃发现科尔与你老婆上了床
When Eva found out that Cole was sleeping with your wife,
她带着一个计划找到你
She came to you with a plan.
是的
Yes.
他背叛了你俩
He had betrayed the both of you.
你们想要报复
You wanted revenge.
他每天与我面对面
The man looked me in the eye every day,
然后去我家  上我的妻子
and then he went to my home, to my wife.
他罪有应得
He deserved what he got.
就是说你们策划了伊娃家发生的袭击事件
So, you staged the attack on Eva in her house?
是的  好让私家侦探看到
Yes, so that P.I. would see it
顺藤摸瓜联系到科尔身上
and the trail would lead straight to Cole.
当然  一切都是假的
It was all for show, of course.
科尔被捕
Cole gets arrested,
伊娃拿到他的钱  从此消失
Eva gets his money and disappears.
伊娃怎么死的呢
So, how did Eva end up dead?
我不知道
I-I don't know.
我第二天早晨跟她通过话
I-I spoke to her the next morning.
她有些焦虑  有些后悔
Eva was stressed-out, regretful.
说这出戏本来也不是她的点子
Said the plan was never her idea in the first place.
那是谁的
Whose plan was it?
不知道
I don't know.
但她有点打退堂鼓
But -- but she was having second thoughts
毕竟她看到科尔要因她的谋杀案被定罪
about seeing Cole convicted for her murder.
她想自首
And she was thinking about coming forward.
那会毁了你  所以你就杀了她
And that would have ruined you, which is why you killed her?
不不  我做的一切都是帮伊娃
No, no, no, no. All I did was help Eva.
她被杀跟我无关
I-I had nothing to do with her murder.
詹姆斯先生
Yeah, mr. James,
你上次见到伊娃是什么时候
when was the last time that you actually saw Eva?
在我们从树林里返回
After we got back from the woods,
我们清理了她家  然后我给了她
we cleaned up her house, and then I gave her a key
一把我们公司住所的钥匙
to one of the company's corporate apartments,
然后我就离开了
And I left.
公司住所
Corporate apartment?
她需要一个住的地方
She needed a place to stay
直到她能出国
until she could get out of the country.
罗伯特·詹姆斯在科尔被杀时
So, Robert James was nowhere near Westchester
根本不在韦斯切斯特附近
at the time of Cole's death.
那就排除了他是两件凶案凶手的嫌疑
That pretty much rules him out for both murders.
也意味着他说了实话
Could also mean he was telling the truth,
这个瞒天过海的点子不是伊娃想出的
that it was someone other than Eva that planned the set up.
我想我知道是谁了
And I think I know who that is.
鉴证组检查了公司住所
CSU checked on that corporate apartment.
他们发现了伊娃的指纹  不过不止这些
They found Eva's fingerprints, but that's not all they found.
我在为科尔的事宜善后
I'm just putting Cole's affairs in order.
很忙  你们需要什么吗
I'm busy. Do you need something?
哈斯金斯女士  我们得告诉你科尔·威特福德的
Ms. Haskins, you should know that Cole Whitfield's blood work
血检结果出来了  发现了高含量的镇定剂
came in, showing high levels of sedatives.
如此之高  他无法自行上吊
So high, in fact, he wouldn't have been able to hang himself.
我们重新核查了他的通话记录
We re-checked his phone records
注意到你给他家打过多次电话
and noticed that you called his house on numerous occasions.
当然打过
Of course I did.
我是科尔公司的总律师顾问
I'm general counsel for Cole's company.
是的  但大部分的来电都是在
Yeah, but most of these phone calls came in
科尔下班后打去的
after Cole was already at work.
伊娃也经常咨询我
Eva consulted with me, as well.
你就是在那时得知她要离婚
That's how you found out her marriage was falling apart
也知道她的婚前协议
and about her prenup.
于是你就不断示意她
So you whispered in her ear,
告诉她如何惩罚科尔
told her how she could punish cole
在这过程中还能拿走一笔钱
and make a little walking-away money in the process.
是吗  我干嘛要这么做
Really? And why would I do that?
我们得知科尔的第一任妻子
You know, we were surprised to learn
玛罗琳是你在大学的
that Cole's first wife, Mallory,
联谊会姐妹时  感到很惊讶
was a sorority sister of yours in college,
你因她的死伤痛不已
And you were devastated by her death.
我们都很痛心
We all were.
但是你告诉朋友们
Yeah, but you were the one that told friends
他杀了她并逍遥法外
that he got away with murder.
为什么过了这么多年
So, why, after all of these years,
你甘愿离开顶级律所
would you leave a top-level law firm
加入科尔的公司呢
to join cole's company?
我有个推理
Here's a theory.
你接受这份工作
You took the job
是想潜入科尔的生活圈
to insinuate yourself into cole's life,
寻找合适的方法
searching for the right way,
合适的时机  为玛罗琳报仇
the right moment to get revenge for Mallory,
你在伊娃身上看到了机会
And you found it with Eva.
太荒唐了
That's absurd.
是吗  伊娃用公司住所
Is it? Eva called your cellphone
的座机给你打了电话
from the the corporate-apartment landline
那时她可"死掉"了
after she was already supposedly dead.
伊娃后悔了
Eva got cold feet.
她想自首  但你却不能允许她那么做
She wanted to come forward, but you couldn't have that,
毕竟你等了这么多年  谋划这么久
not after all those years, after all that planning.
于是你决定把伊娃的假死
So you decided Eva's fake murder
不得不变成真的谋杀
would have to become a real one.
杀掉科尔只是为了避免留下蛛丝马迹
And killing Cole was just a way of tying up loose ends.
很棒的故事  卡塞尔先生
That's an exciting story, Mr. Castle.
也许可以写成一本好书
Maybe it will make a great book,
但这些根本没法立案
but it doesn't make for much of a case.
我们拿到搜查令
We got a warrant.
我们在你的车后箱发现了伊娃的血迹和DNA
We found Eva's blood and DNA in the trunk of your car.
一切都结束了  哈斯金斯女士
It's over, Ms. Haskins.
我深表怀疑
I doubt it.
接下来交给我们
Well, we'll take it from here.
再次感谢
Again, thanks for everything.
她希望谋杀案凶手能被正法
She wanted justice for one murder
却犯下两起谋杀
and ended up committing two of her own.
有件事她说的很对
Well, she was right about one thing.
这故事的确很适合我写本书
This does have all the makings for one of my novels.
只是我不想写
I just don't want to be the one to write it.
走  回家
Come on. Let's go home.
听着  哈维
Hey. Listen, Javi,
配对网的账户资料
Um, about that fake Match.com profile --
很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
我了解  兄弟
I-I know you are, bro.
你如此抱歉  主动要求完成这案子的
In fact, you're so sorry that you're gonna handle
全部文书
all the paperwork for this case.
这样蛮公平
Yeah, that's only fair.
很好  我有约
Cool, 'cause I got a date.
等等  跟史黛西吗
Wait, whoa, whoa, whoa. With Stacy?
不  我跟她不来电
No, no. I wasn't feeling her.
但是我登陆我的账户
But I logged on to my account,
发现一个不错的姑娘叫特雷克西
I and found that there was this lovely girl named Trixie
-她想跟我见面  -特雷克西
- who wanted to meet me. - Trixie --
诵读诗人兼脱衣舞女吗
Uh, the spoken-word poet/exotic dancer?
是啊  赞吧
Yeah. Best of both worlds.
哈维  珍妮和我
Um, Javi, see, uh, Jenny and I --
我们拒绝了她的档案
We purposefully rejected her profile.
我们不想让她跟我们一起
We didn't want the possibility of her going
滑雪度假
on a weekend couples' ski retreat with us.
算你倒霉
Yeah, well, sucks for you...
她会去的
'cause she'll be there.
敬结掉这案子
Okay. To closing the case.
你还好吗
You doing okay?
我被耍了  两个人被杀
I got played and now two people are dead.
那不是你的错
That wasn't your fault.
因为你  杀害二人的真凶被捕
And because of you, two victims have justice.
不过
No, still...
或许是因为当一个私家侦探
Maybe being a private investigator,
有太多的  我也不清楚
there's too much -- I don't know --
模棱两可
Ambiguity.
听着
Look.
你被这案子冲昏了头
Y-you let the case get under your skin, you know?
时有发生
That happens.
也许我不适合干这行
Or maybe I'm just not cut out for this.
你为了当私家侦探付出不少
You know, you put a lot into becoming a P.I.
别轻易下决定
Don't make any hasty decisions.
也许应该睡一觉再说
Maybe you should just sleep on it.
说得对
You're probably right. I should sleep on it.
或许小睡更棒一些
Or perhaps I should nap on it.
小睡很棒
Naps are good.
我强烈支持小睡
I highly advocate naps.